Hyung-Kwon Ko

College of Computing KAIST, Daejeon hyungkwonko@gmail.com https://hyungkwonko.info

About

Hyung-Kwon Ko is a researcher at KAIST Interaction Lab. His main research areas include Human-Computer Interaction, Human-Centered AI, and Information Visualization. He designs, prototypes, and evaluates interactive systems to innovate people's working paradigms based on a thorough investigation of their need. Experienced in AI models from both academia and industry, he is currently interested in how foundation models (e.g., DALL-E) could help people in visual art domains perform creative works.

Education

2019-2021	Seoul National University , Seoul, Korea Master of Science in Computer Science and Engineering (Advisor: Dr. Jinwook Seo)
2014-2019	Hanyang University, Seoul, Korea Bachelor of Science in Mathematics, Minor in Industrial Engineering

Publications

Conference & Journal Papers

[a5] Ko, H.-K.*, An, S.*, Park, G., Kim, S.K., Kim, D., Kim, B., Seo, J. (2022). We-toon: A Communication Support System between Writers and Artists in Collaborative Webtoon

Sketch Revision.

Proceedings of the ACM Symposium on User Interface Software and Technology (UIST '22), 14 pages.

[a4] Jeon, H.*, Ko, H.-K.*, Lee, S., Jo, J., Seo, J. (2022).

Uniform Manifold Approximation with Two-phase Optimization.

Proceedings of IEEE Conference on Visualization and Visual Analytics (VIS '22), 5 pages.

[a3] Jeon, H., Ko, H.-K., Jo, J., Kim, Y., Seo, J. (2022).

Measuring and Explaining the Inter-Cluster Reliability of Multidimensional Projections.

IEEE Transactions on Visualization and Computer Graphics (In Proceedings of VIS '21), 28(1):551-561.

Jung, S., Choe, K., Park, S., Ko, H.-K., Seo, J. (2021). [a2]

Mixed-Initiative Approach to Extract Data from Pictures of Medical Invoice.

IEEE Pacific Visualization Symposium (PacificVis '21), 111-115.

[a1] Ko, H.-K., Jo, J., Seo, J. (2021).

Progressive Uniform Manifold Approximation and Projection.

EG/VGTC Conference on Visualization (EuroVis '21), 133-137.

Preprints & Publications in Progress

[b4] Shin, H., Lee, Y., Ko, H.-K., Kim, J. (2022).

Enabling Prototyping of AI-infused UIs with Task-level Specifications.

(In Progress)

[b3] Ko, H.-K., Park, G., Jeon, H., Jo, J., Kim, J., Seo, J. (2022).

Large-scale Text-to-Image Generation Models for Visual Artists' Creative Works.

Arxiv Preprint (Under Review)

[b2] Choi, J.*, Song, J.*, Jeon, H., Kim, Y., Ko, H.-K., Seo, J. (2022).

How Disentanglement Affects Users' Interpretation, Control, and Sentiment when Using Generative Models.

(Under Review)

[b1] Jeon, H., Aupetit, M., Lee, S., Ko, H.-K., Kim, Y., Seo, J. (2022).

Distortion-Aware Brushing for Interactive Cluster Analysis in Multidimensional Projections.

Arxiv Preprint (Under Review)

Experience

06/2022-Present KAIST Interaction Lab (KIXLAB), Daejeon, Korea

Researcher (Advisor: Dr. Juho Kim)

10/2021-06/2022 Naver Webtoon Corp., Seongnam, Korea

AI Research Scientist, Webtoon AI

04/2021-10/2021 Naver Webtoon Corp., Seongnam, Korea

AI Research Intern, Webtoon AI

03/2019-08/2019 Human-Computer Interaction Lab, Seoul, Korea

Research Intern (Advisor: Dr. Jinwook Seo)

01/2019-02/2019 **LG Electronics**, Seoul, Korea

Research Intern, CTO Division

06/2018-08/2018 Wesleyquest Inc., Seoul, Korea

Research Associate

Honors and Awards

Gary Marsden Travel Award (Full travel support for UIST '22: \$2,800 USD), ACM SIGCHI
Big Data Contest (3rd Place, Prize Money: \$900 USD), NIA and Korea Big Data Forum
AI Novel Writing Competition (2nd Place, Prize Money: \$18,000 USD), KT Corporation and KOCCA
Academic Research Competition (2nd Place, Prize Money: \$180 USD), Hanyang University

Actually 1010

2014-2018 Merit-based Scholarship (6 semesters), Hanyang University

Academic Services

Paper ACM CHI ('22)

Reviewing IEEE PacificVis ('20, '21)

STUDENT ACM UIST ('22)

Volunteering

^{*} denotes equal contributions.